<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on deadfast</title>
    <link>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on deadfast</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>deadfast@proton.io (deadfast)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>deadfast@proton.io (deadfast)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:41199/deadfast/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Better Habits: My Take on Atomic Habits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/atomic-habits-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><author>deadfast@proton.io (deadfast)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/atomic-habits-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just finished reading &lt;strong&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/strong&gt; by James Clear, and honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those books that makes you want to immediately reorganize your entire life. Rating it a solid 9/10.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-core-concept&#34;&gt;The Core Concept&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book revolves around the &lt;strong&gt;compounding effect&lt;/strong&gt; - small changes that seem insignificant at first but compound into remarkable results over time. Clear argues that you don&amp;rsquo;t need massive changes; you need consistent, tiny improvements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways-that-hit-different&#34;&gt;Key Takeaways That Hit Different&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;environment-is-everything&#34;&gt;Environment is Everything&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your environment plays a critical role in defining habit behaviors. The most significant contributor? Your visual environment. Want to break a bad habit? Break your exposure to the cue that triggers it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dune: Overhyped or Underappreciated?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/dune-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate><author>deadfast@proton.io (deadfast)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/dune-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally got around to reading &lt;strong&gt;Dune&lt;/strong&gt; by Frank Herbert after Harrison kept recommending it. My honest take? It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; complicated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first book is genuinely good. Herbert created this incredibly detailed universe with complex politics, ecology, and mysticism all woven together. The world-building is impressive, and you can see why it&amp;rsquo;s considered a sci-fi classic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie (at least the first one) was visually stunning and did justice to the source material. Denis Villeneuve really understood the assignment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Three-Body Problem: Hard Sci-Fi That Hits Different</title>
      <link>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/three-body-problem-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate><author>deadfast@proton.io (deadfast)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/three-body-problem-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Three-Body Problem&lt;/strong&gt; by Cixin Liu is the kind of sci-fi that makes you question everything about humanity&amp;rsquo;s place in the universe. Rating: 8.1/10 (yeah, a lot of my sci-fi reads end up around there).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-makes-it-special&#34;&gt;What Makes It Special&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t your typical Western sci-fi. Liu brings a distinctly Chinese perspective to concepts like fate vs. free will, and it&amp;rsquo;s refreshing. The book feels less about individual heroism and more about humanity as a whole facing an existential threat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sovereign Individual: Prescient or Pretentious?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/sovereign-individual-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate><author>deadfast@proton.io (deadfast)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:41199/deadfast/posts/sovereign-individual-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sovereign Individual&lt;/strong&gt; by James Dale Davidson and Lord William Rees-Mogg is one of those books that either feels like prophecy or pretentious rambling, depending on when you read it. Rating: 7.8/10.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-central-thesis&#34;&gt;The Central Thesis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Written in 1997, the book predicts the rise of digital currencies, remote work, and the decline of nation-states. The authors argue that technology will eventually allow individuals to become &amp;ldquo;sovereign&amp;rdquo; - free from traditional government control and taxation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
